Guide to the DukeMakers records, 2013-2017 UA.31.14.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
DukeMakers
2013-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
UA.31.14.0005
1.5 Linear Feet
DukeMakers is a student maker's group focused on 3D printing, founded in 2014. The DukeMakers records include 3D printed objects created by members of the club as well as some administrative records and other materials.
Biographical / Historical
DukeMakers is a student maker's group focused on 3D printing. The group was founded in early 2014 and is dedicated to teaching the Duke community how to design and print in 3D, experiment with 3D printers, and outreach within Duke and to other organizations. The group drew attention in 2014 by creating a prosthetic hand for a boy with an underdeveloped hand and fashion pieces used in FORM magazine.
Sources: "DukeMakers club innovates with 3-D printing," the Chronicle, 2014 October 01, https://www.dukechronicle.com/article/2014/10/dukemakers-club-innovates-3-d-printing; accessed 2019 October 22.
DukeMakers Facebook page, https://www.facebook.com/pg/DukeMakers/about/?ref=page_internal; accessed 2019 October 22.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The DukeMakers records were received by the Duke University Archives as a gift in 2018.
Collection Overview
The DukeMakers records include 3D printed objects created by members of the club as well as images of additional 3D printed objects, administrative material for the club, documentation for 3D printers, and promotional materials.
Three-dimensional printing; Prosthesis; DukeMakers; Duke University -- Students
- 3D Printed Objects
  - Droplet, 2014 January (Box 1, Item UA31140005-A-0001)
    Scope and Contents
    Thingiverse; solidoodle, Makerware; red, 8.5cm x 6cm x 6cm
  - To Make or Not to Make, 2017 May 10 (Box 1, Item UA31140005-A-0002)
    Ultimaker II, 3D Printer OS with Brim, 15% infill, supports; light grey skull, 12cm x 8cm x 10cm
  - Prosthetic, 2014 September (Box 1, Item UA31140005-A-0003)
    FormLabs FORM 1 material, rigid, uncured, Own Huang '16; blue-green, 9.5cm x 11cm x 5.5cm
  - Duke Chapel, 2017 May 08 (Box 1, Item UA31140005-A-0004)
    Ultimaker II, Navy PLA 40% infill, supports, Henry Quach; navy blue, 21cm x 13cm x 13.5cm
  - Traffic cone, 2016 April (Box 1, Item UA31140005-A-0005)
    Sliced with Simplify 3D, Flash Forge Creator Pro, Nigrui Li '16; grey and orange, 4cm x 4cm x 5.5cm
  - Voronoi Vase, 2014 September (Box 1, Item UA31140005-A-0006)
- Records
  - Images of 3-D printed objects, 2014-2015 (Folder 1)
  - Meeting slides, 2013, 2015 (Folder 2)
  - Memorandums and meeting agendas, 2014 (Folder 3)
  - RepRap Mendel software and machine documentation, 2010 (Folder 4)
  - Article, sign, sticker, 2015 and undated (Folder 5)